{
    "id": "9e27b623d69f4caa96a017994ea472ba",
    "title": "Conditional Sentences Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "If you help Rani, she ………………………… the exam.",
            "description": "In the first conditional we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will pass",
                "would pass",
                "would have passed"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "6c3224f9954644a3a01fd4f87403d5a8"
        },
        {
            "question": "Unless you …………………………. her, she will fail the test.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "help",
                "helped",
                "had helped"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e4a4b83c920b44e4a9829fb7eb4c21dd"
        },
        {
            "question": "If Samuel ………………………. me, I will go to his place.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "invites",
                "invited",
                "had invited"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "a599e5b87ddd48ff8cfdd1df1e9de3fe"
        },
        {
            "question": "If she arrived now, we ……………………………. her.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "can meet",
                "could meet",
                "could have met"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ffabbb7722ff4de59c1ac7d8b0f70d4f"
        },
        {
            "question": "If she ………………………… her money wisely, she wouldn’t be broke now.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "spends",
                "spent",
                "had spent"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d1275c939e074efab65060b6db9b9209"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I ………………………….. his phone number, I would call him.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "know",
                "knew",
                "had known"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "2e55c08b41104b9485985e80fe899c94"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you come home, I ………………………….  you.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will protect",
                "would protect",
                "would have protected"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "a54cbaab3ceb4cee863f41c38f958c59"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ………………………………. to my advice, you would not have been in trouble.",
            "description": "In the third conditional we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "listen",
                "listened",
                "had listened"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "8e8825a4501f4f528a16e2f981f5a82f"
        },
        {
            "question": "If they ………………………….. us, we would have been in trouble.",
            "description": "In the third conditional we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "see",
                "saw",
                "had seen"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "0a400f40cc5c4d38a701659d21fb0460"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ………………………….. respect, you get respect.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "give",
                "gave",
                "had given"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "95966800ac60420e96ee0aa7204bccfb"
        },
        {
            "question": "If she recognized you, why …………………………… she say Hi?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "don't",
                "didn't",
                "hadn't"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "5eff868849e744409965fc51f5641c0f"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you stop talking, I ……………………….. the news.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "can listen to",
                "could listen to",
                "could have listened to"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "9348a9a6bf27488d81cb0caa533346c3"
        }
    ]
}